

Ali Fadhel
Malmö, Skåne län, Sweden
ali.albabily8gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-fadhel-b17513177/

A 26-year-old guy with a huge interest in Data/IT, I started programming six years ago. During these years, I have worked with various tools in several educational institutions. In 2019, I received a vocational education diploma in Java development. Additionally, in June 2023, I completed my Bachelor of Science studies in Computer Science with a specialization in Computer Systems Development at Malmö University.

Strengths:

Social, fast to adapt, good at dealing with stress, self-motivated, flexible, instead of complaining I seek solutions.

Technical Skills:

Java, JavaScript, Node.js, React, HTML/CSS, json, Git, Github, sql-server, MySql, MongoDB, php, C

Experience:

Java developer:

Apr 2018 → May 2018

- Did an Intern at Axis Communications in Lund.
- Implemented a RESTful web service that presents information on any employee within the company upon making a request. The information is gathered from databases to be displayed at any browser in jsonformat later.
- * Technologies used: Java, SpringBoot, Json, MySQL

Full-stack developer:

Aug 2022 → Jan 2023

- ❖ A member of a project called FIPIC at Malmö University.
- We developed a web app that collects responses from children via a form in an innovative way, and then transfer the responses to a database. The app will later be used in a study carried out by students at Malmö University.
- ❖ Technologies used: Node.js, React, Microsoft Azure Database, SQL

Education:

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with specialization in Computer Systems Development – **Malmö University**

Aug 2020 → Jun 2023

Advanced Higher Vocational Education Diploma in Java Developer – EC Utbildning

Sep 2017 → Maj 2019

High School/Upper secondary School, with specialization in information technology – **Pauliskolan**

Jun 2014 > Jun 2016

Apps & Software:

Note: Some of the following projects were built as part of my studies and other in my free time. You can visit the respective link of each project for more information.

My-Movies-List

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily/My-Movies-List

Technologies used: React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose

Chat-app

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily/Chat-App

Technologies used: Java, Swing, Object-oriented programming, Threads, Sockets, Client-Server

My-Characters-Ranking

Demo: https://alialbabily.github.io/My-Characters-Ranking/

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily/My-Characters-Ranking

Technologies used: JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Json, Electron

Online Rock Scissors Paper Like Game

Demo: https://alialbabily.github.io/Online-Rock-Scissors-Paper/

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily/Online-Rock-Scissors-Paper

Technologies used: React, Node.js, Socket.io, Material-UI

Damage-Calculator-App (Calculator like app)

Demo: https://alialbabily.github.io/Damage-Calculator-App/

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily/Damage-Calculator-App

Technologies used: React, Node.js, Material-UI, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

JS Game Prototype

Demo: https://alialbabily.github.io/JS Game Prototype/

GitHub: https://github.com/AliAlbabily/JS Game Prototype

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery